Finding Aid for the James B. Coover Collection of Bibliographic Catalogs, 1690-1994
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Bibliographic catalogs, 1690-1994, I.; Items 1-155
  - Unidentified. Catalogue of Music collected by Sigr. Gaspar Selvaggi of Naples & presented by the Marquess of Northampton to the British Museum, April 1843, 1843-04, circa 75 leaves unnumbered (Box 2, Item 033)
    Additional title: Catalogue of Music collected by Signor Gaspare Selvaggi of Naples and presented to the British Museum by the Marquess of Northampton, April 1843
    Manuscript.
    Named collector(s): Selvaggi, Gaspare
  - Puttick and Simpson. Catalogue of the valuable violins by Cremona and other makers, the property of that eminent violinist Mr. Franc̦ois Cramer ...: which will be sold by auction, by Messrs. Puttick and Simpson ..., 1846-08-22, 5 pages (Box 2, Item 034)
    London (England): Puttick and Simpson
    31 lots
    Named collector(s): Cramer, Franc̦ois
  - Puttick and Simpson. Catalogue of the musical collection of the late John Stumpf, harp and piano manufacturer, comprising original manuscripts of Mozart, Beethoven, & c. ... sold…March 30th, 1847, and following day., 1847-03-30, 7 pages (Box 2, Item 035)
    151 lots. Buyers' names and prices paid marked in original.
    Named collector(s): Stumpf, John
  - Puttick and Simpson. Catalogue of the interesting and valuable musical library of a distinguished collector, in which will be found an excellent selection of the works of celebrated composers of every period and class, highly interesting and valuable scores (comprising many unpublished works,) an unrivalled series of the works of Paesiello, instrumental music, recently published works, numerous theoretical and historical treatises, also musical instruments ... which will be sold by auction by Messrs. Puttick and Simpson, ... on June 25th, and following day …, 1856-06-25, 27 pages (Box 2, Item 036)
    772 lots. Includes interleaves bearing buyers' names and prices.
  - Puttick and Simpson. Catalogue of a collection of music comprising many works of great interest and rarity, autograph compositions, … a few copyrights and music plates, Cardini Cole's pianoforte tutor … also musical instruments, pianofortes by Broadwood, Rust, Griffiths, Lewis, Cramer, Brinsmead, and others … which will be sold by auction by Messrs. Puttick and Simpson … on Friday, December 20th, 1872 …, 1872-12-20, 1 volume (Box 2, Item 037)
    Pages of the catalog have been interspersed with ledger sheets showing prices and buyer names.
  - Puttick and Simpson. Catalogue of the important musical collections formed by the late Thomas Oliphant … comprising printed music, the works of English and Italian composers from the sixteenth century to the present time, many being of the greates interest and rarity, scarce and curious compoisitons in manuscript, both original and transcribed, MS. Collections by Mr. Oliphant on various interesting events, musical and otherwise, to be sold by auction … April 24, 1873, and following day …, 1873-04-24, 44 pages (Box 2, Item 038)
    Additional title: Catalogue of the rare and interesting musical compositions of the late Thomas Oliphant …
    London (England): Puttick & Simpson
    Original
    592 lots. With buyers' names and prices in pencil.
    Named collector(s): Oliphant, Thomas
  - Richard Zeune (Firm). Belle collection de lettres autographes de celebres artistes = Verzeicniss von Autographen beruhmter Kuenstler (Musiker, Sänger und Schauspieler, Maler, Kupferstecher, Bildhauer, Architecten), 1874?, 16 pages (Box 2, Item 039)
    Weimar (Germany): Richard Zeune
    309 lots. "Xxme Catalogue d'autographes"
  - Lodovico Bortolotti & C.. Libretti di melodrammi balli: autograi di musicisti e de altri artisti teatrali presentati all'esposizione musicale in Milano dal Cav. Uff. Damiano Muoni, 1881, 12 pages (Box 2, Item 040)
    Milan (Italy): Lodovico Bortolotti & C.
    53 items. Exhibition catalogue.
    Named collector(s): Muoni, Damiano
  - Arsène Janssens. Vente publique de la collection d'instruments de musique anciens de Arsène Janssens, expert: en la Salle Sainte-Gudule: vendredi 5 mars 1886, 1886-03-05, 16 pages (Box 2, Item 041)
    Additional title: Liquidation pour cause de depart
    Brussels (Belgium): Arsène Janssens (printed by Moens et fils)
    154 items listed.
    Named collector(s): Janssens, Arsène
  - Hôtel Drouot. Catalogue de la collection d'instruments de musique anciens, rares et curieux des XVIIe, XVIIIe et XIXe siècles, tableaux, dessins, gravures..., mobilier moderne... dépendant de la succession de M. Loup... vente 28-30 mai 1888, 1888-05-28, 27 pages (Box 2, Item 042)
    Paris (France): Mondet
    303 lots. Assisted by Gand et Bernardel and M. B. Lasquin.
  - Fievez, J.. Catalogue des instruments de musique anciens armes & antiquities diversees dont las vente… 17 février 1891 et jour suivant…, 1891-02-17, 19 pages (Box 2, Item 043)
    Additional title: Collection de M. E. Landolci, de Sienna
    Brussels (Belgium): J. Fievez, printed by E. Lhoest
    150 lots. Some prices in MS.
    Named collector(s): Landolci, M. E.
  - Artaria & Co.. Verzeichnis von musikalischen Autographen, revidirten Abschriften und einigen, seltenen, gedruckten Original-Ausgaben, vornemlich der reichen Bestände aus dem Nachlasse Joseph Haydn's und Ludwig van Beethoven's, ferner der Manuscripte von Mozart, Schubert, Rossini und anderen namentlich wiener Tonsetzern im Besitze von August Artaria in Wien, 1893, 26 pages (Box 2, Item 044)
    Vienna (Austria): Artaria & Co.
    224 lots. Copied from GB-Lbl.
    Named collector(s): Beethoven, Ludwig van; Haydn, Joseph
  - List & Francke. Antiquarisches lager von List & Francke in Leipzig. Schriften über das Theater, Theoretische und praktische Musik aus dem Nachlasse der Herren Musikdirektor C. Kossmaly in Stettin, Redacteur Dr. J. Schucht in Leipzig, und anderer, 1896, 85 pages (Box 2, Item 045)
    Additional title: Antiquarisches Verzeichnis Nr. 272
    Leipzig (Germany): List & Francke
    2655 lots.
    Named collector(s): Kossmaly, Carl; Schucht, J. (Jean)
  - Leon (Firm). Catalogue de la bibliothèque musicale, théorique et pratique de feu M.E. Helminger, ancien chef de musique militaire et compositeur dont la vente aura lieu à Nice aux enchères publiques dans le courant du mois de janvier 1898 ... à M. Eon bouquiniste, 1897-01, 71 pages (Box 2, Item 046)
    Nice (France): Leon (Firm)
    Circa 250 lots. Leon, bouquiniste. Music, pp.1-51, ca.250 lots, prices fixed and printed.
    Named collector(s): Helminger, M. E.
  - Leo Liepmannssohn (Firm). Catalogue 170: containing ancient works relating to the music, liturgy and the dance from the 15th to the beginning of the 19th century, chiefly from the library of James E. Matthew Esq. of London, 1908, 108 pages (Box 2, Item 047)
    Additional title: Katalog 170: Aeltere Musikliteratur
    Berlin (Germany): Leo Liepmannssohn (Firm)
    1204 lots.
    Named collector(s): Matthews, James E.
  - J.A. Stargardt (Firm). Sammlung Fritz Donebauer, Prag: Briefe, Musik-Manuscripte, Portraits zur Geschichte der Musik und des Theaters; Versteigerung vom 6. bis 8. April 1908, 1908-04-06, 123 pages, plates (Box 2, Item 048)
    Berlin (Germany): J.A. Stargardt (Firm)
    1054 lots.
    Named collector(s): Donebauer, Fritz
  - Karl Ernst Henrici (Firm). Weimars Musenhof: Autographen bedeutender Personen des Weimarer Kreises, sowie hervorragender Zeitgenossen, die persönliche oder literarische Beziehungen zu Goiethe und Schiller unterhielten: zweite Versteigerung der Lagerbestände der Autographenhandlung Otto Aug. Schulz in Leipzig: Versteigerung am 29. u. 20. September, sowie 1. Oktober 1910, 1910-09-29, 62 pages (Box 2, Item 049)
    Additional title: Auktions-Katalog IV
    Berlin (Germany): Karl Ernst Henrici (Firm)
    1048 lots. Photocopies of newspaper clippings from German newspapers bound in.
  - J. Pearson & Co.. Unique and extremely important collection of autograph letters and manuscripts of the world's greatest composers, 1911, 33 pages (11 facsimiles) (Box 3, Item 050)
    London (England): Cheswick Press
    75 lots. Printed in black and red. Many folded plates tipped in.
  - Karl W. Hiersemann (Firm). Musik und Liturgie: darunter besonders alte original Manuskripte, seltene Drucke des 16. Jahrhunderts, eine Abteilung spanische Musik, Original-Tonwerke von Beethoven und Wagner etc.; zum Teil aus der Bibliothek des Don. Federico Olmeda, Presbitero y Maestro de la Capilla de Burgos, und einiger anderer Sammlungen., 1911, 74 pages (Box 3, Item 051)
    Additional title: Katalog 392
    Leipzig (Germany): Karl W. Hiersemann (Firm)
    335 lots.
    Named collector(s): Olmeda, Federico
  - Karl Max Poppe (Firm). Musik. Hierin die Bibliothek des verstorbenen Herrn Kapellmeisters und Musikkritikers Prof. Arthur Smolian, Leipzig. Lager-Katalog No.2., 1912?, 63 pages (Box 3, Item 052)
    Additional title: Lager-Katalog No. 2
    Leipzig (Germany): Karl Max Poppe (Firm), printed by Oskar Bonde
    1738 lots.
    Named collector(s): Smolian, Arthur
  - Camille Vyt (Firm). Catalogue de la bibliothèque de feu M. Florim. van Duyse, musicographe …, 1913-01-21, 46 pages (Box 3, Item 053)
    Ghent (Belgium): Camille Vyt
    716 lots. The catalogue of the sale of 21 Jan. 1913.
    Named collector(s): Duyse, Florimond Van
  - Karl Ernst Henrici (Firm). Musiker-Autographen: Versteigerung Sonnabend, den 25. Januar 1913, 1913-01-25, 17 pages (Box 3, Item 054)
    Additional title: Auktions-Katalog XIII
    99 lots. 4 volumes bound in 1.
    Bound with: Musiker-Autographen; erste Versteigerung der Lagerbestände der Autographenhandlung Otto Aug. Schulz in Leipzig: Versteigerung am 17. September 1910 (Auktions-Katalog III) -- Ludwig van Beethoven: Manuskripte, Briefe, Urkunden ...: Versteigerung Mittwoch, den 7. November 1928 (Versteigerung CXLII) -- Musiker-Autographen ...: Versteigerung Mittwoch, den 7. November 1928 (Versteigerung CXLIII)
  - C.G. Boerner (Firm). Katalog einer wertvollen Bibliothek von Musikbüchern des xv. bis xviii. Jahrhunderts, Versteigerung ... den 2. und ... 3. April 1913 ... durch C.G. Boerner, Leipzig …, 1913-04-02, 140 pages, illustrations (Box 3, Item 055)
    Additional title: Auktions-Katalog 114
    Leipzig (Germany): C. G. Boerner
    624 lots. Running title: Kostbare Musikbücher. Sale material possibly from the library of Alfred Wotquenne.
  - C.G. Boerner (Firm). Musikbücher aus der Sammlung Wagener-Giessen, 1914, 47 pages (Box 3, Item 056)
    Additional title: Lager-Katalog XXVII
    Leipzig (Germany): C.G. Boerner (Firm)
    269 lots. Lager-Katalog XXVII.
  - C.G. Boerner (Firm). Theater und Musik Dramen. Lager-Katalog IV, 1917?, 55 pages (Box 3, Item 057)
    Additional title: Lager-Katalog IV
    Leipzig (Germany): C. G. Boerner, printed by Oskar Bonde
    644 lots.
  - Puttick and Simpson. Catalogue of a highly important collection of original musical manuscripts and autographs of the great masters and composers ... Also a manuscript antiphonarium on vellum by Nicolas Jarry, the first Spanish printed book containing music, and a few other rare music books, which will be sold by auction by Messrs. Puttick and Simpson … on Thursday, November 29th, 1917, 1917-11-29, 28 pages (Box 3, Item 058)
    142 lots, with extra leaves interspersed containing buyer names and prices paid.
  - Sotheby, Wilkinson & Hodge. Catalogue of a very important, interesting & valuable collection of books of airs, ballads, catches, madrigals, songs and other music from the renowned library at Britwell Court … the property of S. R. Christie-Miller, Esq., including many of the scarcest song books of the Elizabethan and Jacobean periods; unique copies of the first (1662) edition of Cantus, songs and fancies, and Psalm tunes to four voices, 1666, printed by John Forbes of Aberdeen, with many other rarities of the first importance which will be sold at auction … the 15th of December, 1919, 1919-12-15, 23 pages (Box 3, Item 059)
    London (England): Sotheby, Wilkinson & Hodge, printed by J. Davy & Sons
    166 lots. With buyers' names and prices fetched in MS.
    Named collector(s): Christie-Miller, Sydney Richardson; Britwell Court (Buckinghamshire, England)
  - Em. Paul (Firm). Catalogue des livres rares et precieux composant la collection musicale de feu…vente du 26 au 29 mai 1920, 1920-05-26, 82 pages (Box 3, Item 060)
    Additional title: Bibliothèque de feu M. Jules Ecorcheville
    Paris (France): Em. Paul
    611 lots with prices fetched. Introduction by Henry Prunieres. Catalog of a sale held 26-29 May, 1920.
    Named collector(s): Ecorcheville, Jules
  - Rudolph Hönisch (Firm). Musik: Antiquariats-Katalog XV, enthaltend u. a. die wertvollen Bibliotheken der Musikprofessoren Dr. Th. Müller-Reuter .. und Dr. H. Reimann …, 1921, 98 pages (Box 3, Item 061)
    Additional title: Catalogue XV of second hand books containing musical works, autographes, biographies, portraits, etc. of musicians, musical bibliography, operas, oratorios and vocal works in full scores, etc. etc. including a collection of Beethoviana, Wagneriana, etc.
    Leipzig (Germany): Rudolph Hönisch (Firm)
    2028 lots.
    Named collector(s): Müller-Reuter, Theodor; Riemann, Hugo
  - Leo Liepmannssohn (Firm). Autographe: Musiker, Bildende Kunstler, Schauspieler, Schriftsteller, Stammbucher, sowie eine Sammlung alter kostbarer Opern- und Oratorien-Textbucher …, 1921-12-02, 86 pages (Box 3, Item 062)
    Additional title: Autographenversteigerung 47
    843 lots. Covers missing. Becoming brittle. Verified in Heidelberger historische Bestande.
  - List & Francke. Alte Hausmusik (-1830) unter Ausschluss der Klavier und Gesangswerke. Katalog 475, 1924, 48 + 4 pages (Box 3, Item 063)
    Additional title: Alte Hausmusik bis zum Jahre 1830
    1169 lots.
  - Lambertini, Michel'Angelo. Bibliophilie musicale. Les bibliothèques portugaises: essai de classification: les livres d'un amateur: cabinet iconographique, 1924, 241 pages (Box 3, Item 064)
    Viseu (Portugal): Tipografia Andrade
    2339 lots. Éd. Abréggée. Classed catalogue of 2,339 items selected mainly as material for the study of musical instruments, and forming the natural complement of a museum of musical instruments founded by the author and acquired by A.A. de Carvalho Monteiro, Lisbon.
  - Dr. Ignaz Schwarz (Firm). Sammlung Georg Eckl. I. Teil: Theater - Musik; Bücher, Blätter und Noten ...: Versteigerung Montag, den 17. Mai 1926 u. ff. Tage, 1926-05-10, 116 pages (Box 3, Item 065)
    Additional title: Versteigerungskatalog XIV
    Vienna (Austria): Buch- und Kunstantiquariat, Auktionsinstitut Dr. Schwarz
    1348 lots. Includes Schatzungspreise fur die Versteigerung der Sammlung Georg Eckl with buyers' names, prices, wrappers, and estimates.
    Named collector(s): Eckl, Georg
  - Leo Liepmannssohn (Firm). Autographen; historische Autographen; literarische Autographen; Musiker, Schauspieler und bildende Künstler; Stammbücher: Versteigerung am Mittwoch, 20. Oktober, Donnerstag, 21. Oktober 1926 ... und am Freitag, 22. Oktober 1926, 1926-10-20, 198 pages (Box 3, Item 066)
    Additional title: Versteigerung 48
    1152 lots (Musiker, 943a- ). Includes price list.
  - Leo Liepmannssohn (Firm). Auktionskatalog Nachlass Wilhelm Heyer, I. - IV, 1926-12-06, 4 volumes in 1 (Box 3, Item 067)
    Berlin (Germany): Leo Liepmannssohn Antiquariat and Karl Ernst Henrici
    4 volumes in 1, each with numerous plates and bound-in estimates.
    Named collector(s): Heyer, Wilhelm
    Contains: I. Versteigerung von Musiker-Autographen aus dem Nachlass des Herrn Kommerzienrates Wilhelm Heyer in Köln: im Geschäftslokal der Firma Karl Ernst Henrici ... 6. ... 7. Dezember 1926, durch Karl Ernst Henrici & Leo Liepmannssohn, Antiquariat; beschreibendes Verzeichnis von Georg Kinsky (120 pages, 15 pages of plates) -- II. Versteigerung von Musikbüchern, praktischer Musik und Musiker-Autographen des 16. bis 18. Jahrhunderts: aus dem Nachlass des Herrn Kommerzienrates Wilhelm Heyer in Köln: im Geschäftslokal der Firma Leo Liepmannssohn, Antiquariat ... 9. Mai und ... 10. Mai 1927, durch Leo Liepmannssohn, Antiquariat & Karl Ernst Henrici; beschreibendes Verzeichnis von Georg Kinsky (114 pages, 18 pages of plates) -- III. Versteigerung von Musiker-Autographen aus dem Nachlass des Herrn Kommerzienrates Wilhelm Heyer in Köln: (dritter Teil): im Geschäftslokal der Firma Karl Ernst Henrici ... 29 September 1927, durch Karl Ernst Henrici & Leo Liepmannssohn, Antiquariat; beschreibendes Verzeichnis von Georg Kinsky (74 pages, 9 pages of plates) -- IV. Versteigerung von Musiker-Autographen aus dem Nachlass des Herrn Kommerzienrates Wilhelm Heyer in Köln: (vierter und letzter Teil): im Geschäftslokal der Firma Karl Ernst Henrici ... 23. Februar 1928 / ǂc durch Karl Ernst Henrici & Leo Liepmannssohn, Antiquariat; beschreibendes Verzeichnis von Georg Kinsky (67 pages).
  - Leo Liepmannssohn (Firm). Autographen: literarische Autographen, historische Autographen, Musiker, Schauspieler und bildende Künstler, Stammbücher, z.T. aus der Sammlung des Herrn Dr. Fritz Jonas: Versteigerung am Freitag, den 10. Juni 1927 ... und am Sonnabend, den 11. Juni 1927, 1927-06-10, 67 pages (Box 3, Item 068)
    Additional title: Versteigerung 50
    697 lots (Musiker, 509 - ). A bit brittle. Includes price list.
    Named collector(s): Jonas, Fritz
  - Karl Ernst Henrici (Firm). Versteigerung von Musikerbildnissen sowie Darstellungen mit Musikinstrumenten aus dem Nachlass des Herrn Kommerzienrates Wilhelm Heyer in Köln ...: Versteigerung Montag, den 12. September 1927 ... Dienstag, den 13. September 1927, 1927-09-12, 58 pages (Box 3, Item 069)
    Additional title: Musiker-Bilbnisse aus der Sammlung Wilhelm Heyer in Köln
    Berlin (Germany): Henrici & Liepmannssohn
    729 lots. Running title: Auktionskatalog Nachlass Wilhelm Heyer.
  - Karl Ernst Henrici (Firm). Musiker-Autographen Sammlung Josef Liebeskind ...: Versteigerung Donnerstag, den 29. September 1927 …, 1927-09-29, 11 pages (Box 3, Item 070)
    Additional title: Versteigerung CXXII
    67 lots. Includes price list. "Auktions-Katalog CXXII."
    Named collector(s): Liebeskind, Josef
  - Karl Ernst Henrici (Firm). Musiker-Autographen in der Hauptsache aus den Sammlungen Friedrich Wilhelm Jähns und Josef Liebeskind, 1927-12-15, 36 pages (Box 3, Item 071)
    Additional title: Versteigerung CXXVI
    206 lots. With buyer's names and prices in MS. List of estimates.
    Named collector(s): Jähns, Friedrich Wilhelm; Liebeskind, Josef
  - Libreria Detken & Rocholl (Naples, Italy). Musica e musicisti: biografie canto, danza, letteratura, musica sacra, spartiti, storia, teatro, tecnica, teoria, ritratti. Sezione antiquaria. Catalogo XI, 1928-10, 56 pages (Box 3, Item 072)
    Additional title: Catalogo XI
    Naples (Italy): Libreria Detken & Rocholl
    692 lots.
  - Leo Liepmannssohn (Firm). Musiker-Autographen. Versteigerung … 16.-17. November 1928 …, 1928-11-16, 124 pages, 6 plates (Box 3, Item 073)
    Additional title: Versteigerung 52
    865 lots. Includes price list.
  - Leo Liepmannssohn (Firm). Musiker-Autographen. Versteigerung Freitag, den 8. März 1929 …, 1929-03-08, 49 pages, 12 plates (Box 3, Item 074)
    Additional title: Versteigerung 53
    369 lots. On cover: Darunter die Originalmanuskripte von Chopins Polonaise in As-dur, op. 53 und von Schuberts Erlkonig. Includes price list.
  - M. Lengfeld'sche Buchhandlung (Cologne, Germany). Musik Geschichte und Theorie. Praktische Musik. Bücher aus den Hauptgebieten des musikalischen Schrifttums. Eine umfangreiche Sammlung 'Das deutsche Lied im 18. Jahrh.' in Originalausgaben. Beethovens Werke in Erst- und Frühdrucken. Instrumental- und Vokalmusik von ca. 1820-1850, darunter C. Ph. E. Bach, Hasse, Mattheson, Reichardt, Telemann u.a.m. Ein Schöffer-Notendruck von 1518. Katalog 36, 1929-10, 119 pages (Box 3, Item 075)
    Additional title: Katalog 36
    Cologne (Germany): M. Lengfeld'sche Buchhandlung
    1851 lots. Bound in, a typed note "Paul Hirsch's copy." Section on "Praktische Musik," bears pencil marginalia, some in code.
  - Leo Liepmannssohn (Firm). Musikmanuskripte Wolfgang Amadeus Mozarts aus dem Besitz von André Erben: im Grünen Saal des Meistersaales, Berlin ... den 12. Oktober 1929 ... durch Leo Liepmannssohn, Antiquariat, Berlin ... beschreibendes Verzeichnis von Georg Kinsky, 1929-10-12, 2 volumes, Textband (44 pages) and Tafelband (13 plates) (Box 3, Item 076)
    Additional title: Versteigerung 55
    Both Versteigerung #55. Bound with Musikmanuskripte Wolfgang Amadeus Mozarts aus dem Besitz von André Erben: ǂb zweiter und letzter Teil: Ausstellung, den 6.-8. Dezember 1932 von 10-5 Uhr; Versteigerung, Freitag, den 9 Dezember 1932 vormittags 10 Uhr, beschreibendes Verzeichnis von Johannes Kahn; Einleitung von Alfred Einstein.
    Named collector(s): André, Johann Anton; Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus
  - Leo Liepmannssohn (Firm). Autographen von Musikern, Schriftstellern, Gelehrten, Naturforschern, bildenden Künstlern, Schauspielern und historischen Persönlichkeiten. Versteigerung Freitag, den 21. November 1930 und Sonnabend, den 22. November 1930 ... Versteigerung 60, 1930-05-20, 102 pages, 13 plates of scores (Box 4, Item 077)
    Additional title: Versteigerung 59
    738 lots. Includes price list.
  - Hellmut Meyer & Ernst. Paganini: Sammlung von Originalporträts und Studienblättern nach dem Leben aus dem Besitz des verstorbenen Geigenvirtuosen B ... Versteigerung Katalog 21. Versteigerung am 19. Dezember 1931, 1931-12-19, 56 pages (Box 4, Item 078)
    Additional title: Versteigerung Katalog 21
    Berlin (Germany): Hellmut Meyer & Ernst
    28 lots. All rectos are illustrations. Paganini's sketches. Includes price list.
    Named collector(s): Paganini, Nicolo
  - M. Lengfeld'sche Buchhandlung (Cologne, Germany). Autographen von geschichtlichen Persönlichkeiten, Dichtern, Schriftstellern, Forschern, bildenden Künstlern und Musikern, zwei Sammlungen aus rheinischen Besitz; beschreibendes Verzeichnis von Georg Kinsky, 1932-11-19, 95 pages, 15 plates (Box 4, Item 079)
    Additional title: Autographen aus rheinischem Besitz
    Cologne (Germany): M. Lengeld'sche Buchhandlung
    571 lots. Katalog Nr. 42. "Musik un bildende Kunst," lots 323-571.
  - Leo Liepmannssohn (Firm). Autographen von Musikern, Schriftstellern, Gelehrten, bildenden Künstlern, Schauspielern, historischen Persönlichkeiten und Naturforschern ...: Versteigerung Freitag, den 9. Dezember 1932, 1932-12-09, 56 pages, 3 music plates (Box 4, Item 080)
    Additional title: Versteigerung 63
    414 lots. Includes price list.
  - Hôtel Drouot. Catalogue des livres sur la musique et partitions provenant de la Bibliothéque de M. Adolphe Jullien, nombreuses partitions avec interessantes dedicaces autographes de C. Cui, Debussy, Delibes, Lalo, Ch. Lecoq, Messager, Reyer, Saint-Saens, Zola, etc. don’t la vente ... 23 Juin 1933 ..., ajoutés et annotés par A. Jullien, 1933-06-23, 52 pages (Box 4, Item 081)
    Additional title: Bibliothèque musicale de M. Adolphe Jullien
    Paris (France): Hôtel Drouot
    217 lots. "Par le ministere de M. Andre Couterier, M. l'administrateur de l'etude de Feu Me. Maurice Ader, assistes de M. Robert Legouix." Lots with buyers' names and prices in pencils.
    Named collector(s): Jullien, Adolphe
  - Gilhofer & Ranschburg (Vienna, Austria). Österreich und die Nachfolgestaaten: wertvolle Bücher und Handschriften aus der Bibliothek Alexander Fürst Dietrichstein, Nikolsburg; Literatur, Almanache, Theaterstücke, Porträts von Schauspielern, Dichtern und Musikern; Theaterszenen, Kostüme und Dekorationen aus der Musik- und Theatersammlung Dr. August Heymann, Wien, 1934-02-27, 75 pages, 15 plates (Box 4, Item 082)